Well, day four was an information dense day.
넷째 날은 정보가 많은 날이었어요
I do hope that you learned some something useful here, and I hope that even those that were already
여러분이 여기서 유용한 걸 배우셨길 바랍니다 이미 토큰이나 컨텍스트 같은 것에
somewhat familiar with things like tokens and context windows picked up a thing or two and are now able
익숙한 분들도 Windows가 픽업한 게 한두 개 있다면 그걸 좀 더 자신 있게
to more confidently put that into practice.
실행할 수 있길 바라요
Certainly this is foundational stuff that we'll be using again and again over the next week or next
이건 기본 기술이고 앞으로 몇 주 동안 계속 사용할 겁니다 이걸
weeks as we build on this and apply it to commercial problems.
토대로 상업적 문제에 적용할 거예요
So what you should now be confident doing is writing code that calls OpenAI and also a llama and using
이제 오픈AI와 llama를 호출하는 코드를 작성해서 지금까지 다룬
it to to summarize the summary use case that we worked on, you can now contrast the leading six frontier
요약 사용 사례를 요약해 보겠습니다 이제 여섯 가지 프런티어 모델을 비교해 보죠
models.
사실 그 이상이죠 왜냐하면 01 미리보기와 GPT 40에 노출됐거든요
zero, and to Claude artifacts and things like that.
클로드 아티팩트 같은 것도요
Um, and in particular, we know that almost all of them are not able to answer the question, how many
특히 이 질문에 답할 수 있는 학생이 거의 없다는 걸 알아요 그
A's are there in the the that sentence?
문장에 A가 몇 개나 들어가는지요
And it's worth pointing out, of course, the reason they struggled with it.
왜 그들이 힘들어했는지도 짚고 넘어갈 필요가 있어요
Now, it should be very clear to you it's because that text is tokenized by the time it's sent in to
보시면 아시겠지만 모델로 전송될 때마다 텍스트가 토큰화되기 때문입니다
the model, and all the model knows about Is tokens.
모델은 토큰에 대해서만 알고 있죠
And so from that perspective, counting letters doesn't mean anything to it, because all it sees is
그래서 그런 관점에서 보면 글자를 세는 건 아무 의미가 없어요 이미 합쳐진
the tokens that are already combined and they don't have the meaning of the letters.
토큰들만 보이니까요 글자의 의미가 없는 토큰들이죠
And that's why it's actually a very difficult question for an LLM, but something like zero one preview
그래서 LLM에 대해 아주 어려운 질문인 겁니다 하지만 01 프리뷰처럼
that's able to think step by step and reason and understands how things need to be spelt, is able to
단계별로 이성과 생각을 할 수 있고 스펠트가 어떻게 필요한지 이해하는 건 가능하죠
Um, and then perplexity was also able to do it too, wasn't it.
당혹스러움도 그 역할을 할 수 있었죠
And I suspect that's because it was able to look that up in its resources of knowledge.
그건 아마 지식을 통해 찾아볼 수 있었기 때문일 거예요
Uh, so also now you've built on top of this to understand about the history of Transformers and how
그 위에 또 다른 건물을 지었잖아요 트랜스포머의 역사와 현재의 모습을 이해하기
we've got to where we are.
위해서요
Tokens and what it means to tokenize context windows and how they're not just the input.
토큰과 컨텍스트 윈도우를 토큰화하는 것의 의미 그리고 어떻게 입력만 하는 것이 아닌지를요
It's the whole conversation so far.
지금까지의 대화 전부요
And now you know about API costs and where to go to look up the costs of APIs and the context windows
이제 API 비용도 알고 API 비용을 어디서 찾을지도 알죠 큰 모델과
associated with the big models.
관련된 컨텍스트 창도요
Okay.
네
Next lecture is going to be exciting.
다음 강의는 정말 재미있을 거예요
You're going to be coding this time.
이번엔 당신이 코딩을 해요
You're going to be building some confidence in your coding against the OpenAI API.
OpenAI API 코딩에 대한 자신감이 생기게 되죠
We're going to use a bunch of different techniques, and you're going to be implementing a business
다양한 테크닉을 사용할 겁니다 여러분은 비즈니스 솔루션을 구현할 겁니다
solution that is more of a wholesale business solution.
도매에 가까운 비즈니스 솔루션이죠
That's going to involve a couple of different calls to LMS, and we're going to get it done in a matter
LMS에 대한 몇 가지 다른 호출이 포함될 겁니다 몇 분 안에 get get을 완료하도록
of minutes.
하죠
And it's a great lab, and it will end with exercise for you.
훌륭한 실험실이고 운동으로 끝날 거예요
So without further ado, uh, let's wrap up for today and I will see you tomorrow for our Big Week one
그럼 지체 없이 오늘은 이만하고 내일 첫 주 프로젝트로 만나요